Register of the America First Committee Records, 1940-1942
Hoover Institution Archives
America First Committee Records
1940-1942
42001
America First Committee.
339 manuscript boxes, 7 oversize boxes, 2 envelopes, 2 motion picture film reels, 1 videotape cassette, 2 film strips, 26 phonorecords (154.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, minutes, reports, studies, financial records, press releases, speeches, newsletters, campaign literature, clippings, photographs, and other audiovisual material, relating to the issue of American neutrality in World War II.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1942.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--1933-1945.; United States--Neutrality.; Video tapes.; Moving-pictures.; Phonorecords.
Container List
- ORGANIZATION DEPARTMENT FILES
  - Charles A. Lindbergh (Box 1.)
  - America First Club Plan - general correspondence
  - America First Club plan of organization
  - Club plan mailings for North Dakota, South Dakota, Wyoming, Pennsylvania, Kansas and Indiana
  - Congressional Districts for 48 states
  - Neutrality vote and miscellaneous materials
  - College chapters, all states
  - Samples of form letters and releases (partial holdings) (Box 2.)
  - Samples of form letters and releases (remainder) (Box 3.)
  - Folders on field and organization men:
    - Robert L. Bliss
    - Page Hufty
    - Sprague - Spencer (Box 4.)
    - Charles L. Smith
    - Joseph R. Boldt, Jr.
    - Arthur Brooks, Jr.
    - Earl Jeffrey
  - Jessamine Hoagland (Women's Clubs)
  - Letters to Senators and Congressmen
  - Pettengill's file to Congressmen
  - March on Washington, D.C. (Box 5.)
  - Foreign correspondence
  - Chapter reactions to C. A. Lindergh's Des Moines speech
  - Report on membership and membership drive
  - Methods of organization: state, district, county, chapter
  - Special campaign - Neutrality Act fight
  - Poster response
  - Report on sound slide film
  - Window display contest
  - Chapter letters - re political set-up and dissolution
  - Chapter chairmen meetings (Box 6.)
  - American Legion VFW miscellany
  - Billboards
  - Bishops and Archbishops letters
  - Chapter accountings for General Wood's contribution of $25.00
  - Draft extension and draft questions
  - Congressional hearings (8) (missing 12/68)
- CORRESPONDENCE BY STATES
  - Alabama - Florida (Box 7.)
  - Florida (contd.) - Illinois (Box 8.)
  - Illinois (contd.) - Indiana (Box 9.)
  - Indiana (contd.) - Iowa (Box 10.)
  - Kansas - Massachusetts (Box 11.)
  - Massachusetts (contd.) - Michigan (Box 12.)
  - Michigan (contd.) - Minnesota (Box 13.)
  - Minnesota (contd.) - Missouri (Box 14.)
  - Missouri (contd.) - New Mexico (Box 15.)
  - Massachusetts, New York (Box 16.)
  - New York (contd.) - North Dakota (Box 17.)
  - Ohio (Box 18.)
  - Ohio (contd.) - Oregon (Box 19.)
  - Oregon (contd.) - Pennsylvania (Box 20.)
  - Rhode Island - Vermont (Box 21.)
  - Virginia - West Virginia (Box 22.)
  - Wisconsin (Box 23.)
  - Wisconsin (contd.) - Wyoming (Box 24.)
- PUBLICITY AND RESEARCH FILES
  - Africa (Box 25.)
  - Agriculture
  - Aiken, Senator George D.
  - Aircraft
  - Alaska
  - America - Britain Defenders
  - America Friends
  - American Peace Mobilization
  - American Youth Congress
  - Appreciate America
  - Army
  - Articles Unused
  - Balkans
  - Bullitt
  - Canada
  - Cartoons
  - Carlson, Anton J. (Box 26.)
  - Clark, Senator and Mrs. Bennett Champ
  - Clark, Senator D. Worth
  - College Men for Defense First
  - Committee of 100 - St. Louis
  - CDAAA literature
  - Washington News-Letter and literature
  - Congressional lists
  - Convoys (Box 27.)
  - Cost of war
  - Council for Democracy
  - Day, Stephen A.
  - Domestic production
  - Far East
  - Feeding Europe
  - Fever Chart
  - Fight for Freedom Committee
  - Fish, Hamilton
  - Flynn, John T. (Box 28.)
  - Foreign policy
  - Foreign trade
  - Friends of Democracy
  - Gallup Poll
  - Gallup Poll - general
  - Germany
  - Grass Roots Movement
  - Greece
  - Greenland
  - Halifax, Lord
  - Hammond, General Thomas
  - Hemisphere Defense
  - Hoover, Herbert
  - Hull, Cordell
  - Hutchins, Robert M.
  - Invasion
  - Johnson, Senator Ed C.
  - Johnson, Hugh
  - Johnson Act (Box 29.)
  - Keep America Out of War Congress
  - Kennedy, Ambassador Joseph
  - Knox
  - Knudson
  - Lamont
  - LaFollette, Philip and Bob
  - Landon, Alfred M.
  - Latin America
  - Lend-Lease Bill (partial holdings) (Box 30.)
  - Lend-Lease Bill (remainder) (Box 31.)
  - Letters to the Editor
  - Lindbergh, Charles A.
  - Longworth, Alice
  - Luce, Henry R.
  - MacNider, Hanford
  - Marquand, Mrs. John P.
  - Ministers' No War Committee
  - Mothers' Groups (Box 32.)
  - Mundt, Karl E.
  - McEnerney, Garret W. (copies of Releases)
  - Mckaig, Ray
  - Various Mothers' Groups
  - National emergency
  - National Council for Prevention of War publications
  - National Committee members biographies, etc.
  - Negotiated peace
  - Navy
  - Neutrality (Box 33.)
  - No Foreign War Committee
  - Nye, Senator
  - O'Brien, Reverend Dr. J. A.
  - 1/3 of a Nation
  - Peek, George N.
  - Pinchot
  - Propaganda
  - Religion
  - Moor, Robin
  - Norris, Kathleen (Box 34.)
  - Roll Call of American Women
  - Roosevelt and Mrs. Roosevelt
  - Rankin, Jeannette
  - Russia
  - Research
  - Sarles, Ruth (see "A History of America First," Ms. D753, A5S24)
  - Torell, A. E.
  - Villard Letter to President
  - Wilkie, Leighton
  - Songs
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 35.)
  - Wood, General Robert
  - Womens groups
  - Youth Committee Against War
  - Speaker - speaker schedule
  - "Pilgrimage to Washington"
  - Referendum
  - Sargent, Porter
  - Stefan, Honorable Karl (Box 36.)
  - Stimson
  - Student Defenders of Democracy
  - Taft, Robert A.
  - American Economic Foundation
  - Citizens No Foreign War Coalition
  - Turkey
  - Thompson, Dorothy
  - Tinkham, Honorable George Holden
  - Tobey, Senator
  - Thomas, Norman
  - Union Now
  - War Aims
  - War Resisters League
  - War Referendum
  - Washington, George
  - Wheeler, Senator Burton K.
  - Willkie, Wendell L. (Box 37.)
  - Uncensored (folder #1)
- SPEAKERS BUREAU FILES
  - State Correspondence (Box 37.)
    - Alabama - Colorado
    - Florida - Maryland (Box 38.)
    - Missouri - North Dakota (Box 39.)
    - Ohio - Vermont (Box 40.)
    - Washington - Wisconsin (Box 41.)
  - Expenses - speakers bureau
  - "Thank you" letters sent to all speakers
  - Radio scripts for chapter use
  - Congratulatory telegram sent to chapter chairmen at time of meeting or rally
  - Book wire urging Armistice Day sermons
  - General name and address book for Speakers Bureau
  - Speakers Bureau Inventory Form, letter to all chapter chairmen (Box 42.)
  - Speakers Bureau chart
  - Bulletins pertaining to Speakers Bureau
  - American Forum of Democracy
  - List of speakers
  - Meetings - chapters - general
  - Chapters' financial classification letter
  - Young Democrats' Convention
  - Your rally
  - Foulis, William S.
  - Suggested letter to clergy
  - Meetings scheduled, concluded
  - Speakers Bureau report file, reports
  - Speakers - miscellaneous
  - Speakers unable to appear
  - Study material for speeches; the speeches
  - Speakers' material (Box 43.)
  - Second tours
  - Congratulations
  - Cartoons
  - Teletype
  - Memos
  - Special memo from Speakers Bureau
  - Financial procedure
  - Adams, Senator
  - Adair, Dr. Fred L.
  - Aiken, George D.
  - Armstrong, O. K.
  - Beal, Howard K.
  - Bolt, Don
  - Bolton, Congressman
  - Barnes, Henry Elmer
  - Baumhart, Jr., Congressman
  - Bazinet
  - Bone, Congressman Homer T.
  - Bradley, Congressman Fred
  - Brooks, C. Wayland
  - Brown, Congressman Clarence J.
  - Burdick, Congressman Usher L.
  - Bushfield, Harlan J.
  - Butler, Congressman John C.
  - Capper, Senator
  - Carroll, Reverend Patrick J.
  - Chavez, Senator Dennis
  - Chenoweth, Congressman
  - Clark, Honorable B. C.
  - Clark, D. Worth
  - Clevenger, Congressman Cliff (Box 44.)
  - Cobb, Irvin S.
  - Coogan, Gertrude
  - Cramm, Fred
  - Crowther, Congressman Frank
  - Danaher, Senator John A.
  - Dancey, Captain S. N.
  - Day, Congressman Stephen A.
  - Donnell, Captain Cushing
  - Durant, Will
  - Dworshak, Congressman Henry C.
  - Elston, Congressman Charles H.
  - Engel, Congressman Albert J.
  - Fish, Hamilton
  - Gillett, Senator Guy M.
  - Gillie, Congressman George W.
  - Gillis
  - Grant, Congressman Robert A.
  - Grau, Phil A.
  - Greeley, Major Horace, Jr.
  - Harness, Congressman Forest A.
  - Helm, Wilbur
  - Hess, Congressman William E.
  - Hill, Knute
  - Hill, Congressman William S.
  - Hillyer, Mary
  - Hoffman, Congressman Clare E.
  - Holt, Honorable Rush D.
  - Hoover, Honorable Herbert R.
  - Houser, Reverend
  - Howard, James Irving
  - Hunter, Congressman John H.
  - Jenkins, Congressman Thomas A.
  - Jensen, Honorable Ben F.
  - Johns, Congressman Joshua L.
  - Johnson, Senator Edwin C.
  - Johnson, Senator Hiram
  - Johnson, General Hugh S.
  - Johnson, Congressman Noble J.
  - Jones, Congressman Robert F.
  - Keefe, Congressman Frank B.
  - Kennedy, Congressman Martin J.
  - Kinzer, Congressman J. Roland
  - Klotsche, J. M.
  - Knutson, Congressman Harold
  - Kohl, Edith E.
  - LaFollette, Philip F.
  - LaFollette, Robert M.
  - Langer, Senator William
  - Lindbergh, Charles A.
  - Lischner, Doctor Hyman
  - Lists...
  - Luckey, Henry C.
  - McAllister, Frank E. (Box 45.)
  - McCarran, Senator Pat
  - MacCracken, Henry Noble
  - McGregor, Congressman J. Harry
  - McLaughlin, Irene Castle
  - MacNider, Colonel
  - Manion, Dean Clarence (North Dakota University)
  - Meetings covered - miscellaneous
  - Monaghan, Reverend Monsignor Hugh J.
  - Morrison, Reverend Charles C.
  - Mundt, Congressman Karl
  - Murray, Frank J.
  - Murray, William H. ("Alfalfa Bill")
  - Norris, Kathleen
  - Nye, Senator Gerald P.
  - O'Brien, Father John A.
  - O'Brien, Congressman Joseph J.
  - O'Connor, Congressman James F.
  - O'Daniel, Senator Lee
  - Olson, W. W.
  - Outstanding letters to Senators, Congressmen
  - Parker, Reverend Louis A.
  - Patterson, Kellogg M.
  - Peek, George N.
  - Pencovic, Dr. F. H.
  - Peterson, Hjalmar
  - Pettengill, Samuel B.
  - Rankin, Jeannette
  - Reed, David A.
  - Reynolds, Senator Robert R.
  - Richards, Congressman James P.
  - Rizley, Congressman Ross
  - Robertson, Congressman Charles
  - Rolph, Congressman Thomas
  - Ross, Robert D.
  - Sauthoff, Congressman Harry
  - Scott, Congressman Hugh D.
  - Scott, Joseph
  - Secrest, Congressman Robert T.
  - Shafer, Paul W.
  - Shanley, Congressman James A.
  - Shipstead, Senator Henrik H.
  - Short, Dewey
  - Simms, Ruth Hanna McCormick
  - Smith, Senator Ellison D.
  - Smith, Congressman Fred C.
  - South, Mr.
  - Speakers, potential - speeches (Box 46.)
  - Springer, Congressman Raymond S.
  - Strange, Michael
  - Stratton, William G.
  - Sumner, Congressman Jessie
  - Swann, Howard G. - publicity for
  - Sweeney, Congressman Martin L.
  - Taft, Senator Robert A.
  - Taft, Mrs. Robert A.
  - Thomas, Norman
  - Toben, Senator Charles W.
  - Van Nuys, Frederick
  - Vorys, Congressman John M.
  - Wade, Bishop R. T.
  - Walker, De Loss
  - Walsh, Senator David I.
  - Wheeler, Senator Burton K.
  - White, Congressman Compton I. (Box 47.)
  - Wheeler's western trip
  - White, Charles Gorwin
  - Williams, Major Alfred J.
  - Willis, Senator Raymond E.
  - Winter, Congressman Thomas D.
  - Wolfenden, Congressman James
  - Woodruff, Congressman Roy O.
- CLIPPINGS FROM CHAPTERS
  - Clippings from Chapters (Box 48.-50.)
- CLIPPINGS FROM NATIONAL HEADQUARTERS
  - Clippings from National Headquarters (Box 51.-54.)
- CORRESPONDENCE OF GENERAL ROBERT E. WOOD
  - Correspondence of General Robert E. Wood (Box 55.-57.)
- FILES OF NATIONAL DIRECTOR, R. DOUGLAS STUART
  - Files of National Director, R. Douglas Stuart (Box 58.-69.)
- CONGRESSIONAL RECORDS
  - March and April 1941 (Box 70.)
  - March 1941 (Box 71.)
  - March, February and January 1941 (Box 72.)
  - January and July 1941 (Box 73.)
  - October and November 1941 (Box 74.)
  - November and December 1941 (Box 75.)
  - January 1942 (Box 76.)
- FINANCIAL CORRESPONDENCE-major contributors
  - A-B (Box 76.)
  - B-E (Box 77.)
  - F-K (Box 78.)
  - K-M (Box 79.)
  - N-S (Box 80.)
  - S-Z (Box 81.)
- MAILINGS, BULLETINS
  - Mailings (Mr. Camphausen's lists) (Box 81.-83.)
  - Sample mailings and letters of criticism (Box 84.-87.)
  - Material furnished the Dies Committee: bulletins, literature and releases (Box 88.-95.)
- FINANCIAL CORRESPONDENCE-general contributors
  - B-All (Box 96.)
  - Bm-Bad (Box 97.)
  - Bah-Bau (Box 98.)
  - Be-Beu (Box 99.)
  - Bi-Bog (Box 100.)
  - Bol-Bre (Box 101.)
  - Bren-Bu (Box 102.)
  - Bue-Cal (Box 103.)
  - Cam-Chi (Box 104.)
  - Chr-Conr (Box 105.)
  - Coo-Cur (Box 106.)
  - Da-Dem (Box 107.)
  - Den-Dor (Box 108.)
  - Dou-Ed (Box 109.)
  - Eh-Et (Box 110.)
  - Fab-Fing (Box 111.)
  - Fis-Fra (Box 112.)
  - Frank-Gar (Box 113.)
  - Gart-Gla (Box 114.)
  - Gli-Greg (Box 115.)
  - Gren-Hae (Box 116.)
  - Hag-Harr (Box 117.)
  - Hart-Helm (Box 118.)
  - Hen-Hin (Box 119.)
  - Ho-Hos (Box 120.)
  - How-Jaco (Box 121.)
  - Jacobsen-Johnson (Box 122.)
  - Johnst-Kelb (Box 123.)
  - Kelli-Kl (Box 124.)
  - Klein-Koh (Box 125.)
  - Kon-Kur (Box 126.)
  - La-Led (Box 127.)
  - Lef-Lo (Box 128.)
  - Lof-Macl (Box 129.)
  - Mag-Mau (Box 130.)
  - May-McM (Box 131.)
  - Me-Mik (Box 132.)
  - Miller-Mora (Box 133.)
  - Mork-Na (Box 134.)
  - Ne-Nu (Box 135.)
  - O-Ov (Box 136.)
  - Pa-Peterson (Box 137.)
  - Peti-Pos (Box 138.)
  - Pr-Rau (Box 139.)
  - Re-Ri (Box 140.)
  - Riche-Rog (Box 141.)
  - Rol-San (Box 142.)
  - Sar-Schi (Box 143.)
  - Schl-Schro (Box 144.)
  - Schu-Sci (Box 145.)
  - Sen-Smith, F. (Box 146.)
  - Smith, K.-Spe (Box 147.)
  - Spi-Sti (Box 148.)
  - Sto-Sum (Box 149.)
  - Sw-Tho (Box 150.)
  - Thom-Tri (Box 151.)
  - U-Vo (Box 152.)
  - Voi-Warn (Box 153.)
  - Was-Wel (Box 154.)
  - Whi-Will (Box 155.)
  - Williams-Wol (Box 156.)
  - Wooda-Za (Box 157.)
  - Zin-Anonymous (Box 158.)
- CHAPTER RECORDS
  - Notebook of maps of chapter locations (Box 159.)
  - Notebook of chapter addresses
  - Files on chapter dissolutions:
    - Alabama-Connecticut
    - Cuba-Indiana (Box 160.)
    - Iowa-New Mexico (Box 161.)
    - New York-Pennsylvania (Box 162.)
    - Philippines-Wyoming (Box 163.)
  - List of chapter headquarters by state
  - October 20, 1941 meeting, Palmer House, Chicago
  - Miscellaneous correspondence before dissolution
  - Miscellaneous correspondence after dissolution
  - A.F.C. Corporations (Box 164.)
  - September 15, 1941 news release
  - Miscellaneous ledgers and notebooks
  - Chapter records by state. (* Indicates that membership index cards are available for these cities and states, and are filed at the end of the collection, boxes 304-336.)
    - Maine
    - Massachusetts: Springfield*, Boston, Worchester (Box 165.-167.)
    - Rhode Island
    - Vermont
    - Connecticut
    - Connecticut (contd.): Hartford, Norwalk, Stamford (Box 168.-169.)
    - New York State: Buffalo*, Cedarhurst*, Hicksville*, Mt. Vernon*, Passaic Valley*, Queens*, Rego Park*, Rockville*
    - New York City (Box 170.-225.)
    - New Jersey: Montclair, Passaic Valley (Box 226.)
    - Florida: Sarasota*, Miami* (Box 227.-228.)
    - Pennsylvania: Philadelphia (Box 229.)
    - Pittsburgh (Box 230.-235.)
    - Maryland: Baltimore* (Box 236.)
    - Virginia: Richmond* (Box 237.)
    - Washington, D.C. (Box 238.-242.)
    - Ohio: Dayton*, Columbus*, Warren* (Box 243.)
    - Indiana: Elkhart*, Gary*, Fort Wayne*, South Bend* (Box 244.-245.)
    - Illinois: Hyde Park*, Loyola*, Mt. Morris*, Riverside*, Carthage*, Crystal Lake*, Rockford*, Evanston (Box 246.-252.)
    - Iowa, Missouri, Nebraska: Des Moines*, Kansas City*, Omaha* (Box 253.)
    - Michigan: Niles, Detroit, Lansing, Grand Rapids (Box 254.-255.)
    - Wisconsin: Appleton, Beloit, Burlington, Bonduel, Chippewa Falls, Eau Claire, Spencer, Seymour, Watertown (Box 256.-257.)
    - Colorado* (Box 258.-265.)
    - Arizona, New Mexico: Phoenix, Glendale, Albuquerque (Box 266.)
    - Utah: Salt Lake City (Box 267.)
    - California: Fresno* (Box 268.)
    - Southern California* (Box 269.)
    - Berkeley* (receipt books at the end of the collection) (Box 270.-273.)
    - Los Angeles* (Box 274.)
    - Washington: Seattle* (Box 275.-276.)
- MISCELLANEOUS OFFICE FILES
  - Mailing lists (Box 277.)
  - Membership lists
  - A.F.C. Bulletins 550-700 (Box 278.-280.)
  - Files on:
    - Neutrality Law
    - Ohio
    - American Legion
    - Publications
    - Oregon
  - News clippings (Box 281.)
  - Letters to Congressmen about Lend-Lease
  - Speeches and articles
  - Article sent to Saturday Evening Post
  - List of committee members
  - Hatch Act
  - Agenda for meetings
  - Minutes of meetings
  - Open letter to President, 10/20/41
  - Tribute to General Wood (Box 282.)
  - Certificate of dissolution
  - Corporate papers
  - Minutes of Directors Meeting on By-Laws
  - Final papers
  - List of committee members
  - Colonel Lindbergh's Des Moines speech
  - Organization of A.F.C. as political, nonincorporated committee
  - Letters about Jan. 29, 1942 meeting
  - William Regnery's advance of $40,000
  - Friends of Democracy, Inc.
  - Lend-Lease Bill
  - Letters to Congressmen
  - 1940 Presidential Election
  - Bad publicity about A.F.C.
  - Correspondence, Sept. 1940-April 1944 (Box 283.)
  - Meeting, 12/11/41 (Box 284.)
  - Chapter letters about dissolution
  - Milwaukee Chapter
  - A.F.C. chapter government
  - Washington News Letter
  - New York Chapter
  - Unanswered letters, 1941
  - Letters received since dissolution
  - Schnibbe, Mr.-correspondence (Box 285.)
  - Bureau of Internal Revenue-correspondence
  - New York Chapter-correspondence
  - Washington, D.C. Research Division-correspondence
  - Organization of chapters-correspondence
  - Sarles, Ruth-correspondence regarding her book
  - Dissolution-correspondence regarding
  - Letters received since dissolution
  - Form letters to chapters (Box 286.)
  - Los Angeles Chapter-correspondence
  - Wood, R. E.-correspondence
  - Sarles, Ruth-correspondence
  - Bliss, R. E.-correspondence
  - Indianapolis Chapter-correspondence
  - Chapters on policy-correspondence with
  - Chicago Chapter-correspondence
  - Material copied from R. E. Wood's file by Ruth Sarles for history
  - Despain, Donald-correspondence (Box 287.)
  - Pugh, Clay-correspondence
  - Georgia Chapter Meetings
  - Washington Meeting, Feb. 24, 1941
  - Field Organization-correspondence
  - Gish, Lillian-correspondence
  - Louisville, Kentucky Meeting
  - Cartoon proofs
  - Telegrams
  - Jewelry, buttons, flags-acquisitions (Box 288.)
  - Form letters
  - Armistice Day
  - List of radio broadcasts from Armistice Week Bulletins
  - Catholic hierarchy and Catholic Laymen's Committee
  - Cartoon service correspondence
  - California
  - Draft extension
  - Miscellaneous
  - Chapters-local and general
  - Internationalists
  - Form letters sent to newspapers (Box 289.)
  - Case, Otto A.-correspondence
  - Farmers
  - Hertzberg, Syndey-correspondence
  - Hagood, General Johnson-correspondence
  - Hammond, General T. S.-correspondnece
  - Howell, G. O.-correspondence
  - College poll
  - Judson, Clay-correspondence
  - Minnesota
  - O'Brien, Reverend John A.-correspondence
  - Landon, Alfred M.-correspondence
  - Fraser, Willard E.-correspondence
  - Lisehner, Dr. Hayman-correspondence
  - New York Chapter
  - Publicity-Wheeler Trip (Box 290.)
  - Radio broadcasts
  - Polls
  - Form letters
  - Cross-section of letters to chapters
  - National Committee correspondence
  - Material used in writing history
  - Old peace movement
  - Correspondence from interested supporters (Box 291.)
  - College polls
  - Schnibbe, H. C.-correspondence
  - Letters on new principles
  - Sarles, Ruth-miscellaneous historical materials from
  - University & College (Box 292.)
  - Telegrams
  - Historical material
  - Lend-Lease bill (Box 293.)
  - Lindbergh, Charles-clippings
  - Radio complaints
  - Clippings
    - Roosevelt
    - Military incidents
    - Vote on war
    - Russian religion
    - General
    - Editorials
    - Catholic material
  - A.F.C. Bulletins reproduced
  - Clippings-cartoons (Box 294.)
  - Clippings-miscellaneous (Box 295.)
  - Newsletters, campaign literature, and clippings (Box 296.)
  - Full page advertising (Box 297.)
  - A.F.C. Newsletters
    - Impeachment of Roosevelt
    - Research Bureau newsletters
    - Impeachment of Secretaries Knox and Stimson
    - Against aid to Russia
    - For national referendum
    - For impregnable defense
    - Against sending postcards
    - Against Lend-Lease
    - Letters to Congressmen
    - LaFollettes and A.F.C.
    - Political backing for isolationists
    - Neutrality debate in Senate
    - Connection with Nazis
  - Speakers' schedules
  - Newsletters & campaign literature (Box 298.)
  - Reports on membership
  - Mail reports
  - Clippings from PM
  - Campaign literature (Box 299.-301.)
  - Printed matter (Box 302.)
  - Newsclippings from Colorado Chapter
  - Sample copies of the A.F.C. newspaper
  - Campaign literature and buttons (Box 303.)
  - Card Indexes (Box 304.)
    - Mailing and membership lists
    - College and individual contacts
    - California (Box 305.)
      - Fresno, members
      - Glendale, members
      - Los Angeles (Box 306.)
        - Subscription list of newspapers
        - Volunteer list
        - Mailing list, A-C
        - Mailing list, D-Z (Box 307.)
        - Cancelled subscriptions (Box 308.)
        - Subscription applications
        - Subscription list for individuals
        - Financial list
        - List of supporters by Congressional District (Box 309.)
        - Master file of membership applications, A-G (Box 310.)
        - Master file of membership applications, H-M (Box 311.)
        - Master file of membership applications, N-S (Box 312.)
        - Master file of membership applications, T-Z (Box 313.)
      - San Francisco (Box 314.)
        - Members
        - List of Governors and Congressmen
      - General, members (Box 315.)
    - Colorado (general), members
      - Denver (Box 316.)
        - Members, A-J
        - Members, K-Z (Box 317.)
      - Western slope and unprocessed applicants (Box 318.)
    - Connecticut, general
    - Connecticut
      - East Hartford, members
      - Norfolk, members (Box 319.)
      - Norfolk, list of signers of petition to President, May, 1941
      - West Norfolk, members
      - Hartford, members
      - Stamford, signed membership cards (Box 320.)
      - Hartford, new members
    - District of Columbia
      - Local mailing list
      - National and Congressional mailing list (Box 321.)
      - Membership list
    - Florida, members (Box 322.)
    - Illinois, members
      - Hyde Park, members
      - Riverside, members